QI CHEN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EDUCATION

BS of Computer Science, Dean's List

University of Memphis/TN/2011 - 2015

Platform by Per Scholas

Specialized IT Training / NY/ 2019

Trained to understand and analyze the basics of Big Data and Hadoop technologies through hands-on activities, case studies,

and group projects. Learned how to extract, scrub, and manipulate real-time and warehouse data using SOL & Java.

SKILLS

Java	
Python	
C++	
MySQL	
Hive	
Sqoop	
Oozie	
AWS	
VMWare	
MapReduce	
Hadoop	
Linux	
API: JDBC	

REFERENCES

John-Paul Wenger

Technical Support Lead
Dahua Technology

T: 562-704-6533

E: jp.wenger@dahuatech.com

•	646-598-1337	0	github.com/swordwielder
\searrow	qchen125@gmail.com	in	linkedin.com/in/qifchen

PROFILE

Data and Analytics specialist with experience in surveillance security industry in tech roles with focus in Data Modeling, Scheduling, Big Data, and Data Distribution. Hold a BS Degree in Computer Science with four years of programming and 10 years of customer service experience utilizing software from Google Analytics to Salesforce.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INDEPENDENT CONSULTANT

Freelance / New York, NY / 2019

· Created a Discord bot that gives real live weather, crypto and stock data through API calls in Python

PRODUCT ENGINEER, TECHNICAL WRITER & CONTENT MANAGER

Dahua Tech USA Inc. / Irvine, CA / 2015 - 2018

- Updated and maintained Dahuawiki.com to provide better technical support to the customers including adding YouTube tutorials with 7000 daily hits on website tracked through Google Analytics.
- · Hardware testing/support for clients including but not limited to NVRs, DVRs, IP Cameras, and Analog Cameras via Salesforce.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Center for Information Assurance, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2015

• Researched types of Authentication & add findings to Articulate Storyline for students

COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR

Computer Science Learning Center, University of Memphis, Memphis, TN / 2014 - 2015

- · Helped students with coursework and checked coding errors
- Taught & Mentored high school students with interests in Computer Science in the field of game development using Ren'Py

TECHNICAL ASSISTANT

ITS Service Desk, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2013 - 2015

· Assisted campus students with troubleshooting U of M services including E-learn, UMDrive, portal via Helpdesk using campus SupportSuite software